I've walked the avenues of life,
I've tasted rain and summer's heat.
I've gathered pearls of wisdom, simply beautiful,
And laid them down here at the Teacher's feet.
The world is organized in such complexity,
The Architect is found in every stone.
But even when survival needs are met,
A hunger stays for something still unknown.
For truth is knowledge as things really are,
A light that shines on what is yet to come.
Science isn't blind and faith isn't lame
When we see them both as one.
It's a fuller way of walking on the road
Where every path to truth is joined together.
We're chasing down the meaning of our days,
By the love of God directed, now and ever.
I've built my intellectual altars to the mind
Through philosophy and arts and the sciences.
I've analyzed the patterns and the laws
And let my thinking be my sole reliance.
But academic means can only go so far,
They're limited by things we can't perceive.
We're ever learning, never coming to the truth
Without the courage to truly believe.
Why is there something rather than nothing at all?
Does who I am persist beyond the grave?
I'm reaching for the eyes that have been hidden,
For the spirit that the Savior came to save.
I choose to experiment upon the word.
I choose the foresight of the prophecy.
The spirit speaks what senses never heard—
It's the power of God that sets the seeker free!
So I'll walk in wondering humility,
Recognizing that I know so very little.
The world may shift like shadows on the wall,
But a simple truth is resting in the middle.
Great ignorance might lead a man to fear,
And knowledge brings a measure of our sorrow.
But wisdom brings a peace that's resting here
And a hope for every bright tomorrow.
Life has grand purpose.
A beautiful and simple way.
In the name of Jesus Christ,
Amen.